[Music]
Hello and welcome to this session on
what's new in Algo for GitHub
productivity enhancements. My name is
Sebastian and I'm a software engineer in
the business central engineering system
team and one of the primary developers
on ALG go. Today I would like to talk
about productivity enhancements.
All those small features we have made
since last time which does not fit into
our other major sessions on telemetry
and custom templates. In modern software
development, even small inefficiencies
can quickly add up. They can take time
away from your important development
work and that's why we are focused on
delivering a series of improvements
which will speed things up for you and
minimize the risk of errors.
First up, we have improvements for
deployment and builds.
I would like to start with environment
variables. So, right now, you can put
settings in both your repo variables and
organization variables, but now it's
also possible to put them in your
environment variables. These should be
named ALGO environment settings and can
be defined for each of your
environments.
It should be noted these are available
only during deployment jobs and
therefore not all of your settings
should be put into this variable. A good
example is the deploy to setting. This
can now be defined in environment
variables and can be defined for each
environment. This will help declutter
your main settings and will allow you to
define them per environment where you
need them.
There are a few limitations. Like I said
before, since this runs during the
deployment job, we do not support the
runs on shell and continuous deployment
properties. If you still wish use these,
you should define them in your main
settings file like you do currently or
in your organization or repository
settings files. Up next, we have the
ability to block pull requests on new
warnings.
The fail on setting has existed for a
while, but it now accepts a new value,
new warning. What this does is it
compares the list of warnings generated
in your pull request build and compares
them to the last good CICD build. If any
new warnings are introduced, your pull
request will be blocked. This does not
run on your CAC job. So even if that
introduces any new warnings, your CICD
will not be blocked. Up next, we have
page scripting test visualizer. So, page
scripting has been supported for a while
now, but what's new is we can now
visualize the results of your page
scripting tests directly in your build
summary. This is similar to your regular
and performance tests. All you have to
do is enable page scripting like you did
before. No new setting is needed. This
will just work out of the box and show
up in your build summary as long as
you're running page scripting tests. The
next category is improvements for
reliability and usability.
First up, we have workflow input
validation.
So, this is a new feature that runs in
the background and allow us to validate
the input to your workflows
and fail workflows as early as possible
if anything goes wrong. A good example
is the create release workflow. So
currently it's possible for you to input
a version number in an incorrect format.
What this will do is it will still run
the workflow partially, create a release
and attack in your repository, but the
workflow will then fail. This means you
have to manually clean up and start the
workflow again. With this new
improvement, we will fail the workflow
as early as possible, saving you time
and allowing you to create a new run as
quickly as possible.
For now, this is implemented only for
create release and increment version,
but is made in a flexible way that will
allow us to extend this to other
workflows going forward. Next is
settings. So, algo has a lot of
settings. It's probably difficult to
remember the name of all of them,
especially if you were new. It can be
very intimidating to look through the
whole list and get an overview. with
schemas for settings. This now becomes
much easier in an IDE like Visual Studio
Code. You will now get also complete
like shown in the screenshot which will
help you discover
uh settings more easily. On top of that,
we also have uh tool tips for settings
and a link directly to the documentation
for that specific setting. So, you don't
have to manually open the settings
documentation and find the setting. You
can now go there directly from your ID.
And finally, I like to talk about debug
logging. This is probably not something
that you will use much, but it will help
us help you.
When reporting an issue to us on the
ALGO uh repository,
we typically ask you to upload files.
Now we would like to ask you to run
these with enable debug settings um in
GitHub as shown in the screenshot. This
is a built-in GitHub feature. What's new
is that we have focused on putting extra
logs that will help us debug your issues
in here. The reason for this is this
will not clutter your regular logs which
might be useful to you but provide
information to us which will help us
debug your issues quicker and easier.
That's it for this session. Thanks for
watching. I hope you enjoyed and I
encourage you to watch our other
sessions on telemetry and custom
templates. Thank you.